<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cups of Code</title><link>/</link><description>Recent content on Cups of Code</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>Copyright © 2021, Cups of Code</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to get your first interviews as a software engineer</title><link>/posts/how_to_get_first_interviews_as_a_software_engineer/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/how_to_get_first_interviews_as_a_software_engineer/</guid><description>Finding a job is never easy - finding the first job is a thousand times harder. Getting those automatic rejection emails without having a chance to interview can be an emotional roller-coaster that makes you doubt your skills, abilities, and intentions. This is why striving for visibility is key when trying to land that first job interview.
The greater the number of people who view your resume, the greater the chance of being offered an interview - it&amp;rsquo;s as simple as that.</description></item><item><title>When and how to use RxJava Disposable</title><link>/posts/when_how_use_rxjava_disposable_serialdisposable_compositedisposable/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/when_how_use_rxjava_disposable_serialdisposable_compositedisposable/</guid><description>Disposable RxJava 2 introduced the concept of Disposables .
Disposables are streams/links/connections between Observer and Observable. They&amp;rsquo;re meant to give power to the Observers to control Observables. In most cases, the Observer is a UI element, ie; Fragment, Activity, or a corresponding viewmodel of those elements. While Observable represents a data flow where data can be passed from one source to another and get modified along the way if needed.</description></item><item><title>How to choose mobile app development course online?</title><link>/courses/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/courses/</guid><description>There are so many different courses, tutorials, and instructions out there for you to learn mobile development. In the sea of options, it’s important to understand what will help you be ready in the professional workplace and excel in programming.
While there are some teachers that can explain the concept well, you may leave the class asking yourself how can you apply this knowledge. And it’s because these teachers don’t have the experience building and shipping professional apps.</description></item><item><title>Good and sad examples of extension functions</title><link>/posts/good-and-sad-extensions/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/good-and-sad-extensions/</guid><description>This article is based off my talk at Droidcon SF this year. Kotlin is well-known for null-safety and extension functions features among android developers. Extension functions provide the ability to make new functionality of an extending class without making changes to it. In addition, the new functionality can be declared outside of the extending class. They&amp;rsquo;re also very beneficial when you want to tweak an api that can&amp;rsquo;t be modified.</description></item><item><title>How to display notifications in 2020</title><link>/posts/how-to-display-notification-in-2020/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/how-to-display-notification-in-2020/</guid><description>These days, most startup apps heavily rely on third-party libraries to send push notifications to a user, thus causing developers to usually not pay too much attention to Android notification changes.
For example, I was working on my side-project which sends a notification once the download is completed (was checking how DownloadManager works).
Back in 2016, you&amp;rsquo;d need to initialize NotificationManager and pending intent if notification contains custom action:
1private lateinit var notificationManager: NotificationManager 2private lateinit var pendingIntent: PendingIntent 3 4override fun onCreate(savedInstanceState: Bundle?</description></item><item><title>Recap of 2019: the art of speaking</title><link>/posts/recap-of-2019/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/recap-of-2019/</guid><description>There is a saying in Russian “как лодку назовешь, так она и поплывет”[a boat sails in accordance with its name]. So January 1st I declared the 2019 to be more bold, tenacious and eager. And oh, has it been! 2019 was a roller-coaster of challenges and rewards.
A few things have shaped this year:
Personally, I hardly ever ask people for anything I want or need. But I can definitely ask someone to do a favor to help family, friends, and colleagues.</description></item><item><title>Talks</title><link>/talks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/talks/</guid><description>The list of the talks I&amp;rsquo;ve given in the past. They&amp;rsquo;re primarily focused on Android Development and Kotlin language. If you would like me to speak at your event, please fill out this form .
2021: Name Conference/Meetup Location Date Video  Slides Employment and Employability Trends Asia Pacific University Of Technology and Innovation Kuala-Lumpur, Malaysia March 2021 &amp;mdash; &amp;mdash; MVI in a nutshell Women Developer Academy USA, North America May 2021 &amp;mdash; Slides Why would teachers want to know about coding Android Apps?</description></item><item><title>How not to abuse extensions in Kotlin</title><link>/posts/how_not_to_abuse_extensions_in_kotlin/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/how_not_to_abuse_extensions_in_kotlin/</guid><description>Kotlin extensions are very practical. They help to reduce the boilerplate of the code.
Code highlight example: fun &amp;lt;T&amp;gt; Context.getComponent(clazz: Class&amp;lt;T&amp;gt;): T { return this.applicationContext.getSystemService(clazz.name) as T }
Gist:
Tweet: I&amp;#39;m in love with `SpannableStringBuilder` extensions. Did not know it&amp;#39;s been out since 2017! #android #androidDev pic.twitter.com/sgGskizj4j
&amp;mdash; Aida (@Aida_Isay) September 14, 2019 Practice, practice, practice
The End!</description></item><item><title>About Me</title><link>/about/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/about/</guid><description>Hi there 👋 ! My name is Aida Issayeva. I&amp;rsquo;m a Sr.Android Engineer with over 6 years of experience (as of March 2021) building and scaling Android Apps from the ground up.
Interested in working with me? Fill out this form and I&amp;rsquo;ll get back to you within 2-3 days.
I like to share tidbits of knowledge I&amp;rsquo;ve gathered throughout the years. Some of them may be very specific to Android development, some of them are about general software development, and some are about soft skills that are helpful in a career.</description></item><item><title/><link>/social/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/social/</guid><description>✨ Latest Blog Post ✨ 💯 Work with me 💯 🎉 Android Kotlin Nanodegree 🎉 📹 Tiktok 📹 📸 Insta 📸</description></item></channel></rss>