<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cups of Code</title><link>http://cupsofcode.com/</link><description>Recent content on Cups of Code</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>Copyright © 2019, Aida Issayeva</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2020 00:52:59 +0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://cupsofcode.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to choose a good course for learning mobile development</title><link>http://cupsofcode.com/courses/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://cupsofcode.com/courses/</guid><description>There are so many different courses, tutorials, and instructions out there for you to learn mobile development. In the sea of options, it’s important to understand what will help you be ready in the professional workplace and excel in programming.
While there are some teachers that can explain the concept well, you may leave the class asking yourself how can you apply this knowledge. And it’s because these teachers don’t have the experience building and shipping professional apps.</description></item><item><title>How to display notifications in 2020</title><link>http://cupsofcode.com/post/how-to-display-notification-in-2020/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://cupsofcode.com/post/how-to-display-notification-in-2020/</guid><description>These days, most startup apps heavily rely on third-party libraries to send push notifications to a user, thus causing developers to usually not pay too much attention to Android notification changes.
For example, I was working on my side-project which sends a notification once the download is completed (was checking how DownloadManager works).
Back in 2016, you&amp;rsquo;d need to initialize NotificationManager and pending intent if notification contains custom action:
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 private lateinit var notificationManager: NotificationManager private lateinit var pendingIntent: PendingIntent override fun onCreate(savedInstanceState: Bundle?</description></item><item><title>Recap of 2019: the art of speaking</title><link>http://cupsofcode.com/post/recap-of-2019/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://cupsofcode.com/post/recap-of-2019/</guid><description>There is a saying in Russian “как лодку назовешь, так она и поплывет”[a boat sails in accordance with its name]. So January 1st I declared the 2019 to be more bold, tenacious and eager. And oh, has it been! 2019 was a roller-coaster of challenges and rewards.
A few things have shaped this year: 1. Personally, I hardly ever ask people for anything I want or need. But I can definitely ask someone to do a favor to help family, friends, and colleagues.</description></item><item><title>Good and sad examples of extension functions</title><link>http://cupsofcode.com/post/good-and-sad-extensions/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://cupsofcode.com/post/good-and-sad-extensions/</guid><description>This article is based off my talk at Droidcon SF this year.
Kotlin is well-known for null-safety and extension functions features among android developers. Extension functions provide the ability to make new functionality of an extending class without making changes to it. In addition, the new functionality can be declared outside of the extending class. They&amp;rsquo;re also very beneficial when you want to tweak an api that can&amp;rsquo;t be modified.</description></item><item><title>Talks</title><link>http://cupsofcode.com/talks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://cupsofcode.com/talks/</guid><description> The list of the talks I&amp;rsquo;ve given in the past. They&amp;rsquo;re primarily focused on Android Development and Kotlin language. If you&amp;rsquo;d like me to speak at your event, please send me a message on social media (the links are in nav bar above).
2019 Name Conference/Meetup Location Date &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Video&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Slides Reactive approach to delegation in Kotlin Android Summit McLean, VA, USA August 2019 Slides Reactive approach to delegation in Kotlin GDG DevFest Sydney, Australia November 2019 ____ Slides Reactive approach to delegation in Kotlin Droidcon SF San Francisco, CA, USA November 2019 Slides Level up your extension game Droidcon SF San Francisco, CA, USA November 2019 Slides</description></item><item><title>About me</title><link>http://cupsofcode.com/about/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://cupsofcode.com/about/</guid><description>Hi there!
My name is Aida Issayeva. I&amp;rsquo;m a Sr.Android Engineer with over 6 years of experience(as of March 2021) building and scaling Android Apps from the ground up.
The apps I built and worked on:
ThoriumX LiquidSky Clarity Money Marcus As you see they range from satellite communication to finTech to cloud gaming service industries.
On this blog I share tidbits of knowledge in software development I&amp;rsquo;ve gathered while building and scaling the apps.</description></item></channel></rss>