<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Technical Documentation on Cups of Code</title><link>https://cupsofcode.com/categories/technical-documentation/</link><description>Recent content in Technical Documentation on Cups of Code</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>Copyright © 2024, Cups of Code</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cupsofcode.com/categories/technical-documentation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>6 Rules Every Platform Engineer Should Know for Crafting Clear Technical Announcements - Part III</title><link>https://cupsofcode.com/post/day_14_6_rules_every_platform_engineer_should_know_for_crafting_clear_technical_announcements_part_3/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cupsofcode.com/post/day_14_6_rules_every_platform_engineer_should_know_for_crafting_clear_technical_announcements_part_3/</guid><description>This article is a Part III of my series on crafting clear technical announcements.
Part I is available here . Part II is here .
Rule 5: Write Short Sentences Writing short sentences is a powerful technique for enhancing clarity and engagement in technical communications.
Each sentence should adhere to the principle of &amp;ldquo;One Sentence == One Idea&amp;rdquo;, where sentence conveys a single, clear thought without overloading the reader. Reducing the use of subordinate clauses, such as:</description></item><item><title>6 Rules Every Platform Engineer Should Know for Crafting Clear Technical Announcements - Part II</title><link>https://cupsofcode.com/post/day_13_6_rules_every_platform_engineer_should_know_for_crafting_clear_technical_announcements_part_2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cupsofcode.com/post/day_13_6_rules_every_platform_engineer_should_know_for_crafting_clear_technical_announcements_part_2/</guid><description>This article is a continuation of my series on crafting clear technical announcements.
If you missed Part I, you can catch up here . Stay tuned for Part III, which will be available via this link tomorrow.
In this installment, we will dive deeper into another 2 essential rules that help platform engineers communicate more effectively with their teams and stakeholders.
Rule 3: Reduce &amp;ldquo;There Is/There Are&amp;rdquo; Usage Developers love using &amp;lsquo;There is/There are&amp;rsquo; in their sentences when referring to issues, learnings, or just about everything.</description></item><item><title>6 Rules Every Platform Engineer Should Know for Crafting Clear Technical Announcements - Part I</title><link>https://cupsofcode.com/post/day_12_6_rules_every_platform_engineer_should_know_for_crafting_clear_technical_announcements_part_1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cupsofcode.com/post/day_12_6_rules_every_platform_engineer_should_know_for_crafting_clear_technical_announcements_part_1/</guid><description>The way you craft and structure technical announcements is key to capturing and retaining the attention of developers.
Developers are:
natural problem-solvers with a keen ability to see through unclear (aka, BS) information many are non-native English speakers, which makes clear and structured communication even more critical. In these series, you&amp;rsquo;ll learn 6 essential rules to help you craft clear technical announcements.
Rule 1: Use Active Voice Using active voice in technical writing is crucial for clarity and engagement.</description></item></channel></rss>