<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Personal on Cups of Code</title><link>https://cupsofcode.com/categories/personal/</link><description>Recent content in Personal on Cups of Code</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>Copyright © 2023, Cups of Code</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cupsofcode.com/categories/personal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Tracking My Way to Joy: A Year-Long Experiment of Self-Care and Personal Growth</title><link>https://cupsofcode.com/post/tracking_my_way_to_joy_with_notion/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cupsofcode.com/post/tracking_my_way_to_joy_with_notion/</guid><description>Table Of Contents: Prerequisites New Formula Setup 1. Track 2. Plan 3. Reflect Results Final Thoughts Prerequisites A year into COVID lockdown I started noticing how my attention span has gone down dramatically. Often I’d forget why I even stepped into a room or simply what was the next thing I wanted to do. Having these symptoms with a full-time job, side-projects I wanted some traction on, home needs, and rental property requests was not easy.</description></item><item><title>2022 Year in Review</title><link>https://cupsofcode.com/post/2022_review/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cupsofcode.com/post/2022_review/</guid><description>Table Of Contents: Personal Highlights Professional Highlights Challenges The Year in Numbers Content Personal Growth Finances Time wasters In the World Best of the Year Looking Ahead Every year I like to take some time to reflect on the past 12 months. I think about all of my favorite moments and experiences from the year and consider what lessons I’ve learned along the way.</description></item><item><title>2021 Year in Review</title><link>https://cupsofcode.com/post/2021_review/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cupsofcode.com/post/2021_review/</guid><description>Table Of Contents: Highlights of 2021 Professional Timeline Goals Stats: Everything Else: Annual retrospectives are a great way to look back and analyze all the milestones you’ve overcome, what went wrong, and what areas could use some improvement. For as long as I can remember, I’ve been doing end-of-year recaps where I’d sit down and track the previous 12 month-long journeys on paper for my own eyes only.</description></item><item><title>Recap of 2019: the art of speaking</title><link>https://cupsofcode.com/post/recap-of-2019/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cupsofcode.com/post/recap-of-2019/</guid><description>There is a saying in Russian “как лодку назовешь, так она и поплывет”[a boat sails in accordance with its name]. So January 1st I declared the 2019 to be more bold, tenacious and eager. And oh, has it been! 2019 was a roller-coaster of challenges and rewards.
A few things have shaped this year:
Personally, I hardly ever ask people for anything I want or need. But I can definitely ask someone to do a favor to help family, friends, and colleagues.</description></item></channel></rss>