<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Personal on Cups of Code</title><link>https://cupsofcode.com/categories/personal/</link><description>Recent content in Personal on Cups of Code</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>Copyright © 2024, Cups of Code</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cupsofcode.com/categories/personal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A Question I’ve Been Asking Myself Lately (And Why)</title><link>https://cupsofcode.com/post/day_27_a_question_i_ve_been_asking_myself_lately_and_why/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cupsofcode.com/post/day_27_a_question_i_ve_been_asking_myself_lately_and_why/</guid><description>I spend a lot of time contemplating the leap from a full-time job to starting my own business.
But lately, the question that has been on my mind is:
Why haven&amp;rsquo;t I jumped into entrepreneurship first? There are a few reasons for my hesitation:
Reason #1: Lack of a Clear Idea: I don’t yet have a solid concept for my business. I&amp;rsquo;m unsure about the problem I’d be solving, and starting a business without a clear purpose doesn&amp;rsquo;t lead to success.</description></item><item><title>A Lesson My Parents Taught Me That I’ll Never Forget</title><link>https://cupsofcode.com/post/day_25_a_lesson_my_parents_taught_me_that_ill_never_forget/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cupsofcode.com/post/day_25_a_lesson_my_parents_taught_me_that_ill_never_forget/</guid><description>When I was 13 or 14, I learned a lesson from my parents that I&amp;rsquo;ll never forget:
If you want a healthy work-life balance you should leave work concerns at the workplace. Here&amp;rsquo;s what happened:
One day, I came home from school extremely upset. Something had happened that seriously bothered me, so much so that I couldn’t stop talking about it while helping my mom and sister prepare dinner, and continued to vent throughout the meal.</description></item><item><title>The 2 Most Difficult Choices I’ve Ever Had To Make In Life</title><link>https://cupsofcode.com/post/day_24_2_most_difficult_choices_ive_ever_had_to_make_in_life/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cupsofcode.com/post/day_24_2_most_difficult_choices_ive_ever_had_to_make_in_life/</guid><description>When I was in my early twenties, I decided to pursue a better life and financial independence.
Of course, whenever we set goals in life, life tests us. And I was no exception.
These were the 2 most difficult choices I&amp;rsquo;ve ever had to make in life—and both directly impacted my goal of establishing a secure and prosperous future.
Hard Choice #1: Moving to the USA Moving to the USA in my early twenties was one of the toughest decisions I&amp;rsquo;ve ever made.</description></item><item><title>3 Simple Steps to Help You Stay Resilient and Focused</title><link>https://cupsofcode.com/post/day_23_3_simple_steps_to_help_you_stay_resilient_and_focused/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cupsofcode.com/post/day_23_3_simple_steps_to_help_you_stay_resilient_and_focused/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s not easy staying motivated.
Especially when your goal is to change your state of mind.
For every negative state of mind, there are at least three simple steps to lift your spirits and change your emotional path:
&amp;ldquo;If you&amp;rsquo;re unhappy, start with the body. Nourish it. Rest it. Move it.&amp;rdquo; Caring for your body is the first step to shifting your mood—physical well-being lays the groundwork for emotional resilience.</description></item><item><title>The One Software App I Can’t Live Without For Handling My Life</title><link>https://cupsofcode.com/post/day_8_the_one_software_app_i_cant_live_without_for_handling_my_life/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cupsofcode.com/post/day_8_the_one_software_app_i_cant_live_without_for_handling_my_life/</guid><description>Today, there is an app, website, or software platform for just about anything (including finding someone to walk your dog).
But when it comes to managing my life, there is one app I can&amp;rsquo;t live without:
Notion And here&amp;rsquo;s why: Reason #1: It has seamless integration with many tools, making it a single source of truth for all action items across different tools such as emails, calendars, documents, and other project tracking apps.</description></item><item><title>3 Realizations About Task Management To Finish Your To-Do List By The End Of Each Day</title><link>https://cupsofcode.com/post/day_5_3_realizations_about_task_management_to_finish_your_to-do_list_by_the_end_of_each_day/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cupsofcode.com/post/day_5_3_realizations_about_task_management_to_finish_your_to-do_list_by_the_end_of_each_day/</guid><description>Realization 1: Prioritize Tasks Effectively As an adult, the list of things to do never ends.
Something always pops up, needs your urgent attention, or is waiting to be scheduled. To manage these tasks effectively, you need to prioritize them. Often, prioritization is based on importance, urgency (deadlines), or a combination of both.
By prioritizing tasks based on importance and urgency, you can manage your responsibilities better.
Realization 2: Use A Single Tracking System As an adult, you receive action items from various sources—emails, calendars, Jira, documents, spreadsheets, phone calls, and more.</description></item><item><title>How I Got Interested in Building Scalable Systems for my life</title><link>https://cupsofcode.com/post/day_4_how_i_got_interested_in_building_scalable_systems_for_my_life/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cupsofcode.com/post/day_4_how_i_got_interested_in_building_scalable_systems_for_my_life/</guid><description>I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t call myself an expert in productivity or system design.
However, I have spent 5,000 hours reading and learning about productivity and system design. And I have probably spent 3,000 hours practicing and integrating these concepts into my own life.
Here&amp;rsquo;s how I first became interested in building a scalable system for my own life: It was the summer of 2021. I was falling behind on work, duties related to a rental property, personal projects, and meeting with friends and family.</description></item><item><title>Day 1: Why I'm Starting To Write Online</title><link>https://cupsofcode.com/post/day_1_why_i_m_starting_to_write_online_ship30for30/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cupsofcode.com/post/day_1_why_i_m_starting_to_write_online_ship30for30/</guid><description>I recently signed up for Dickie Bush &amp;amp; Nicolas Cole&amp;rsquo;s cohort-based course, Ship 30 for 30.
Here are a few reasons why: To unclutter and consolidate my thoughts into cohesive, digestible material. To build a consistent habit of daily writing. To embrace the mindset of publishing something rather than pursuing perfection. Over the next 30 days, I plan on writing about Android Development, Developer Experience, and Productivity.
Join me on this adventure—and let me know if you have any questions along the way!</description></item><item><title>Tracking My Way to Joy: A Year-Long Experiment of Self-Care and Personal Growth</title><link>https://cupsofcode.com/post/tracking_my_way_to_joy_with_notion/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cupsofcode.com/post/tracking_my_way_to_joy_with_notion/</guid><description>Table Of Contents: Prerequisites New Formula Setup 1. Track 2. Plan 3. Reflect Results Final Thoughts Prerequisites A year into COVID lockdown I started noticing how my attention span has gone down dramatically. Often I’d forget why I even stepped into a room or simply what was the next thing I wanted to do. Having these symptoms with a full-time job, side-projects I wanted some traction on, home needs, and rental property requests was not easy.</description></item><item><title>2022 Year in Review</title><link>https://cupsofcode.com/post/2022_review/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cupsofcode.com/post/2022_review/</guid><description>Table Of Contents: Personal Highlights Professional Highlights Challenges The Year in Numbers Content Personal Growth Finances Time wasters In the World Best of the Year Looking Ahead Every year I like to take some time to reflect on the past 12 months. I think about all of my favorite moments and experiences from the year and consider what lessons I’ve learned along the way.</description></item><item><title>2021 Year in Review</title><link>https://cupsofcode.com/post/2021_review/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cupsofcode.com/post/2021_review/</guid><description>Table Of Contents: Highlights of 2021 Professional Timeline Goals Stats: Everything Else: Annual retrospectives are a great way to look back and analyze all the milestones you’ve overcome, what went wrong, and what areas could use some improvement. For as long as I can remember, I’ve been doing end-of-year recaps where I’d sit down and track the previous 12 month-long journeys on paper for my own eyes only.</description></item><item><title>Recap of 2019: the art of speaking</title><link>https://cupsofcode.com/post/recap-of-2019/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cupsofcode.com/post/recap-of-2019/</guid><description>There is a saying in Russian “как лодку назовешь, так она и поплывет”[a boat sails in accordance with its name]. So January 1st I declared the 2019 to be more bold, tenacious and eager. And oh, has it been! 2019 was a roller-coaster of challenges and rewards.
A few things have shaped this year:
Personally, I hardly ever ask people for anything I want or need. But I can definitely ask someone to do a favor to help family, friends, and colleagues.</description></item></channel></rss>