<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Ship 30 for 30 on Cups of Code</title><link>https://cupsofcode.com/categories/ship-30-for-30/</link><description>Recent content in Ship 30 for 30 on Cups of Code</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>Copyright © 2024, Cups of Code</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cupsofcode.com/categories/ship-30-for-30/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How I Got Interested in Building Scalable System for my life</title><link>https://cupsofcode.com/post/day_4_how_i_got_interested_in_building_scalable_system_for_my_life/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cupsofcode.com/post/day_4_how_i_got_interested_in_building_scalable_system_for_my_life/</guid><description>I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t call myself an expert in productivity or system design.
However, I have spent 5,000 hours reading and learning about productivity and system design. And I have probably spent 3,000 hours practicing and integrating these concepts into my own life.
Here&amp;rsquo;s how I first became interested in building a scalable system for my own life: It was the summer of 2021. I was falling behind on work, duties related to a rental property, personal projects, and meeting with friends and family.</description></item><item><title>The Best Way To Get Started Learning About Android Development</title><link>https://cupsofcode.com/post/day_3_the_best_way_to_get_started_learning_about_android_development/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cupsofcode.com/post/day_3_the_best_way_to_get_started_learning_about_android_development/</guid><description>I love learning about Android Development.
Unfortunately, when I first got interested in Android Development, I had a hard time figuring out where to start.
So, if you are trying to learn more about Android Development, here&amp;rsquo;s the best way to get started: Read This Blog: Developer Guides by Google will give you a lay of the land, and is a helpful way to get your bearings.
Take This Course: Android Kotlin Developer Nanodegree by Udacity is a must-read beginner resource for anyone interested in Android Development.</description></item><item><title>3 Essential skills that define a software engineer</title><link>https://cupsofcode.com/post/day_2_3_essential_skills_that_define_a_software_engineer/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cupsofcode.com/post/day_2_3_essential_skills_that_define_a_software_engineer/</guid><description>Being able to code doesn&amp;rsquo;t make you a software engineer, although coding is a fundamental skill and a prerequisite for becoming one.
Anyone can write code that compiles and runs thanks to a wide range of IDEs (integrated development environments). Here are three important skills that transform you into a software engineer:
Skill #1: Robustness Writing code that works in ideal conditions is one thing, but ensuring that it operates under various edge cases, unexpected inputs, and adverse conditions is another.</description></item><item><title>Day 1: Why I'm Starting To Write Online</title><link>https://cupsofcode.com/post/day_1_why_i_m_starting_to_write_online_ship30for30/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cupsofcode.com/post/day_1_why_i_m_starting_to_write_online_ship30for30/</guid><description>I recently signed up for Dickie Bush &amp;amp; Nicolas Cole&amp;rsquo;s cohort-based course, Ship 30 for 30.
Here are a few reasons why: To unclutter and consolidate my thoughts into cohesive, digestible material. To build a consistent habit of daily writing. To embrace the mindset of publishing something rather than pursuing perfection. Over the next 30 days, I plan on writing about Android Development, Developer Experience, and Productivity.
Join me on this adventure—and let me know if you have any questions along the way!</description></item></channel></rss>