<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Ship 30 for 30 on Cups of Code</title><link>https://cupsofcode.com/categories/ship-30-for-30/</link><description>Recent content in Ship 30 for 30 on Cups of Code</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>Copyright © 2024, Cups of Code</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cupsofcode.com/categories/ship-30-for-30/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>One Tip Every Junior Software Engineer Needs to Hear to Succeed</title><link>https://cupsofcode.com/post/day_7_1_tip_i_would_give_someone_who_wants_to_become_a_software_engineer/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cupsofcode.com/post/day_7_1_tip_i_would_give_someone_who_wants_to_become_a_software_engineer/</guid><description>Are you a junior software engineer eager to make your mark?
I have been working as a software engineer for 9 years now. And what I can tell you (from experience) is that in order to succeed in this industry you need not only to write code, cover unhappy paths and edge cases, and decide on trade-offs, and other things.
So, here’s the one crucial tip every junior software engineer needs to hear as you advance in your career:</description></item><item><title>The One Software App I Can’t Live Without For Handling My Life</title><link>https://cupsofcode.com/post/day_8_the_one_software_app_i_cant_live_without_for_handling_my_life/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cupsofcode.com/post/day_8_the_one_software_app_i_cant_live_without_for_handling_my_life/</guid><description>Today, there is an app, website, or software platform for just about anything (including finding someone to walk your dog).
But when it comes to managing my life, there is one app I can&amp;rsquo;t live without:
Notion And here&amp;rsquo;s why: Reason #1: It has seamless integration with many tools, making it a single source of truth for all action items across different tools such as emails, calendars, documents, and other project tracking apps.</description></item><item><title>2 Steps For Android Developers To Integrate Dependabot Under 10 Minutes And Automate Dependency Updates</title><link>https://cupsofcode.com/post/day_6_2_steps_for_android_developers_to_integrate_dependabot_under_10_minutes_and_automate_dependency_updates-copy/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cupsofcode.com/post/day_6_2_steps_for_android_developers_to_integrate_dependabot_under_10_minutes_and_automate_dependency_updates-copy/</guid><description>Step 1: Enable Dependabot Security Updates Enabling Dependabot security updates in GitHub allows you to automatically receive patches for vulnerabilities in your project&amp;rsquo;s dependencies.
This feature scans your project repositories for dependencies and checks them against a database of known security vulnerabilities. By doing so, it helps ensure that your codebase remains secure from exploits found in outdated or compromised libraries. The updates are proposed as pull requests, making it easy to review and merge the necessary changes into your main branch.</description></item><item><title>3 Realizations About Task Management To Finish Your To-Do List By The End Of Each Day</title><link>https://cupsofcode.com/post/day_5_3_realizations_about_task_management_to_finish_your_to-do_list_by_the_end_of_each_day/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cupsofcode.com/post/day_5_3_realizations_about_task_management_to_finish_your_to-do_list_by_the_end_of_each_day/</guid><description>Realization 1: Prioritize Tasks Effectively As an adult, the list of things to do never ends.
Something always pops up, needs your urgent attention, or is waiting to be scheduled. To manage these tasks effectively, you need to prioritize them. Often, prioritization is based on importance, urgency (deadlines), or a combination of both.
By prioritizing tasks based on importance and urgency, you can manage your responsibilities better.
Realization 2: Use A Single Tracking System As an adult, you receive action items from various sources—emails, calendars, Jira, documents, spreadsheets, phone calls, and more.</description></item><item><title>How I Got Interested in Building Scalable Systems for my life</title><link>https://cupsofcode.com/post/day_4_how_i_got_interested_in_building_scalable_systems_for_my_life/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cupsofcode.com/post/day_4_how_i_got_interested_in_building_scalable_systems_for_my_life/</guid><description>I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t call myself an expert in productivity or system design.
However, I have spent 5,000 hours reading and learning about productivity and system design. And I have probably spent 3,000 hours practicing and integrating these concepts into my own life.
Here&amp;rsquo;s how I first became interested in building a scalable system for my own life: It was the summer of 2021. I was falling behind on work, duties related to a rental property, personal projects, and meeting with friends and family.</description></item><item><title>The Best Way To Get Started Learning About Android Development</title><link>https://cupsofcode.com/post/day_3_the_best_way_to_get_started_learning_about_android_development/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cupsofcode.com/post/day_3_the_best_way_to_get_started_learning_about_android_development/</guid><description>I love learning about Android Development.
Unfortunately, when I first got interested in Android Development, I had a hard time figuring out where to start.
So, if you are trying to learn more about Android Development, here&amp;rsquo;s the best way to get started: Read This Blog: Developer Guides by Google will give you a lay of the land, and is a helpful way to get your bearings.
Take This Course: Android Kotlin Developer Nanodegree by Udacity is a must-read beginner resource for anyone interested in Android Development.</description></item><item><title>3 Essential skills that define a software engineer</title><link>https://cupsofcode.com/post/day_2_3_essential_skills_that_define_a_software_engineer/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cupsofcode.com/post/day_2_3_essential_skills_that_define_a_software_engineer/</guid><description>Being able to code doesn&amp;rsquo;t make you a software engineer, although coding is a fundamental skill and a prerequisite for becoming one.
Anyone can write code that compiles and runs thanks to a wide range of IDEs (integrated development environments). Here are three important skills that transform you into a software engineer:
Skill #1: Robustness Writing code that works in ideal conditions is one thing, but ensuring that it operates under various edge cases, unexpected inputs, and adverse conditions is another.</description></item><item><title>Day 1: Why I'm Starting To Write Online</title><link>https://cupsofcode.com/post/day_1_why_i_m_starting_to_write_online_ship30for30/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cupsofcode.com/post/day_1_why_i_m_starting_to_write_online_ship30for30/</guid><description>I recently signed up for Dickie Bush &amp;amp; Nicolas Cole&amp;rsquo;s cohort-based course, Ship 30 for 30.
Here are a few reasons why: To unclutter and consolidate my thoughts into cohesive, digestible material. To build a consistent habit of daily writing. To embrace the mindset of publishing something rather than pursuing perfection. Over the next 30 days, I plan on writing about Android Development, Developer Experience, and Productivity.
Join me on this adventure—and let me know if you have any questions along the way!</description></item></channel></rss>